when the virus is how they invented
когда вирус так они изобрели
[music] it’s
[музыка]
interesting
интересно
so you decide in iran the village is
так то вы определитесь в иране селе
terrible
грозное
well but how do you support
хорошо а вот как вы поддерживаете вот
this carcass they call you special operations
эту тушу вас называют спецоперации
against whether
против ли
nina and
nina а
what for
что за
45 45
45 45
you won’t say that’s why you
вы не скажете вот из-за чего вы
support
поддерживаете
tell me because  why do you support this
скажите из-за чего вы поддерживаете эту
what you call operations
то что у вас называют операции
[music
[музыка]
] refugees run with him
вам с ним бегут беженцы
they run away or they are taken out
они бегут или их вывозят
[music]
[музыка]
look look we were closed to them
смотри смотри у нас были закрыты на них
why they couldn’t leave before kwam
почему они не могли раньше квам выехать
two months three months ago
два месяца за три месяца назад
htm here  look, what prevented them
htm вот смотрите а что им мешало уехать
from leaving Mariupol before you started
из мариуполя до того как вы начали
bombing
бомбить
a year ago a year ago if
по года назад год назад если тут так
it was so bad here,
плохо было а
but now it’s bad ah-yes-yes-yes, the introduction of Russian
то сейчас плохо а-да-да-да ввода русских
troops was good,
войск было хорошо правда
really, this was good life was good, everything is
вот этим было хорошо жилось хорошо все
fine, but
нормально а
when and
когда а
when the Russian army came to the Russian,
когда пришла русская армия российской
more precisely, so Russia, you will be Russian
точнее так россии ты будешь там русских
sky there, then the Russians, that is, they began to live
небо то россияне то есть им стало жить
poorly,
плохо
but look, that is, it turns out that
да вот смотрите то есть получается у
my friends lived in Mariupol lived
меня знакомые жили в мариуполе жили
normally while Russian  the army didn’t start
нормально пока русская армия не начала
bombing, they left here,
бомбить они уехали сюда
look, wait, but what happened to them, something
смотрите подождите а а что с ними что то
was wrong, all these years they were killed with them,
было не так вот эти все годы с ними их
or what, but if you didn’t know
убивали или что а вот а если не знали
what you were talking about, then
чем вы говорите тогда
well, that’s it,
ну так вот то есть вот
well, you don’t like the authorities  for example, what
ну власть не нравится например что
does the government mean, you don’t like it, for example,
значит власть не нравится вот например
you don’t like some kind of president there,
вам не нравится там какой-то президент
like, well, what do you live - yes,
типа ну и что живете - да
that is, you still have Russian, and
то есть вы еще до сих пор да
even we have Russian in the region,
еще даже мы в области есть русский язык
look in Ukraine, the state language is
смотрите в украине государственный язык
Ukrainian, so this is normal in France
украинский так это нормально во франции
French, so to speak, let them
французских так говоря блок пусть
speak the block, but from the state and teaching in the
говорят но от государства и обучение на
Ukrainian Foreign Ministry, one thing is the problem in
украинском миде одну в чем проблем в
your schools, let's say in what
ваших школах давайте в грозном на каком
language do children learn
языке изучают дети
very much and in Chechen
очень и на чеченском
so don't wait wait wait
чтоб не подождите подождите подождите
math mathematics in Chechen
математику математику на чеченском или
or Russian is taught
на русском преподают
however in what language  what language
однако на каком на каком языке в школе
do you teach mathematics at school,
преподают математику у вас
but in what Russian or Chechen
но на каком по-русски или по чеченски
does the sail tell mathematics and look in Chechen, that is, in Russian
посмотрите то есть в российской
federations have Russian as the
федерации есть русский язык
state language and therefore
государственные и поэтому в чечне и
don’t look at mathematics in Chechnya so why in Ukraine
не смотрите так почему в украине
why in Ukraine it
почему в украине не на украинском языке
should not be
должно преподаваться
taught in Ukrainian  Chechnya teaches not in the
в школах в чечне преподает не на
Chechen language, but in Russian
чеченском языке а на русском
which
которых
parents
родители
and Russian
и русский
watch,
смотрите а
otherwise you are not a brand, but whoever you are Russian
то вы не а марка да кто бы вы русская
, then it turns out from his studies right
так получается тогда него от учебы прямо
behind the quiet and cooking,
за тихий а варка
well
ну
[music]
[музыка]
doesn’t sing, but you are Russian Russian, let’s already
не то поет а вы русская русская давай аж
see  because those who do know
вижу потому что те которые таки знаете
they envy you are a nationalist, how is it
они завидуют вы националист как это
Russian yes, I see yes you are for the Russian language,
русская да я вижу да вы за русский язык
let them be rich, let the bard of children in
пусть богатов пусть барда детей в
Mariupol, then let the children of Mariupol be
мариуполе то пусть детей мариуполе
bombed, but so that you have a peaceful sky,
бомбят но чтобы у вас было мирное небо
but look again two months two
но смотрите еще раз два месяца два
months ago in  it was peaceful in
месяца назад в мариуполе было мирно
mariupol no one touched anyone everything calmly and
никто никого не трогал все спокойно и
peacefully lived someone killed in mariupol
мирно жили кого-то убивали в мариуполе
at least one person for tongues
хоть одного человека за языки лиза что
liza lived with bad luck  well, or they were killed, and
жилось жила с нехорошо или их убивали и
that is, because someone,
то есть из за того что кому-то вот
for example, you don’t like something, they
например у вас не нравится чем-то путин
don’t like Putin,
не понравится
depending on who interfered with them, then if
смотря кто кто им мешал тогда если тут
it was so bad to leave three months ago in
было так плохо уехать три месяца назад в
Russia, or
россии а
maybe they are simply taken out, or maybe  they
может их вывозят просто а может их
are taken out
вывозят
tender look how how they got how they
нежную смотри как как они попали как они
got in honor
попали в честь
how they got to chechnya how they got
как они попали в чечню как они попали аж
from mariupol to
из мариуполя в чечне вы сами приехали
chechnya  deportation look they are citizens of
это депортация смотреть они граждане
ukraine, including deity so they deport her
украины то в том числе и deity так ее
why why they didn’t go to russia three months ago before the
почему почему они три месяца назад до
invasion of Russian troops
вторжения русских войск они не выезжали
they completely bombed the city look
им разбомбили полностью город смотрите
you bombed them people themselves lived like this
вы разбомбили им люди себе жили таким
something they liked something not in  russia did not
что-то нравилось что-то не в россию не
go hay buds on them they needed so
ехать бутонов сено на им нужно было так
you bombed the city in general completely
вы им разбомбили город вообще полностью
they have nowhere to live no you bombed you
им негде жить не вы это вы бомбили вы
bombed because your power and you
бомбили потому что ваша власть и вы
support
поддержите
no no you girl you  responsible for
нет нет вы девушка вы ответственный за
this war because before in it
эту войну потому что до в ее
you support it you said I
вы ее поддерживайте вы сказали я
support it means you took the
поддерживаю значит вы на себя взяли
moral responsibility for this
морально ответственный за это
minute and you support them
минуты и вы поддерживает у них не
forbade your husband there,
не но смотри ты запретила своему там
drown on a contract, but you are all but you
мужу топите на контракт но ты всю но ты
support morally this war
поддерживаешь морально это эту войну
means you will hold it
значит ты подержишь
no I think that this operation is right
нет я считаю что правильно эта операция
look at
посмотри
you if you say no they won’t cancel but do
вы если скажете нет не отменят но и не
n’t then you can say yes and
надо тогда может говорить да и
[music]
[музыка]
here you are to me  say here do you think
вот вы вы мне говорите сюда вы считаете
that yes it’s right this special operation
что да правильно это спецоперация
is being done
делается
came out above I was told that
вышли выше мне говорили что
let’s
давайте
turn on the record here at
включила сюда включилась пластинка в
eight years old let’s
восемь лет давайте
who I’ll ask then I don’t know what
кто вот я спрошу то я не знаю что
so far
пока
look
смотрите
yes what is given what did you call donbass
да что дан что как вы назвали донбасс
or donbass
или донбасс
people
людей
from
оттуда
there look at that  top look look
вот то смотрите топ смотрите смотрите
this you are not hiding behind the people from
это вы не прикрываетесь людьми из
mariupol to win the people of mariupol do not
мариуполя выиграть люди мариуполь не
look you are in now you have announced that you
смотрите вы в теперь вы озвучили что вы
don’t want to do it because of NATO
из-за нато не хотите да
but look, I understand, that is, you look,
да смотрите я понял то есть вы смотрите
you cynically just came on and deceived
цинично только что прехали обманывали
that this is because people there people
что вот это из за того что там людей
people people didn’t like something and
людям людям что-то не нравилось так и
because of this you attacked
из-за этого вы напали
look until then I’ll ask your opinion this is
смотрите до тех я спрошу мнение вот это
yours  colleagues before in a striped T-shirt
ваши коллеги до в полосатой футболочки
you look yesterday from the moment I see my mother
вы смотрите вчера от момента я вижу мама
because she is more vigorous for an hour she says
тк она более ядрёна на час она говорит
you look yes, look yesterday in
вы смотрите да вот смотрите вчера в
Odessa Russian rockets hit a residential house
одессе русской ракеты попали в дом жилой
killed eight people and a three-month-old
убили восемь человек и трехмесячного
baby
ребенка
[music]
[музыка]
behave like I really
ведут себя как действительно
destroy
уничтожаю
there  Mariupol,
есть мариуполь
that is, who is bombing Mariupol with aviation,
то есть а кто бомбит с авиацией
our troops,
мариуполь наши войска
that you still look again, but how ours
что все еще раз смотрите а как наши наши
fly over Mariupol if our
летают над мариуполем если наших
planes are not there
самолетов там нет
completely and completely, he already thought about
целиком и полностью он уже задумался о
what smells of some kind of nonsense
что пахнет какой-то ерундой
Western who are the authorities or someone
западные кто власти или кто-то
close  Biden have already begun to
приближенные байдена уже начали
think about the fact that this is some kind of
задумываться о том что это какая-то
garbage that this is a provocation,
[__] что это идет провокация задумались
they thought after the situation, so please think with
они после ситуации вот и подумайте
your head when they have a
пожалуйста своей головой когда им
dock  zat
доказать
but look, besides your Chechnya
а вот смотрите вы кроме своей чечне
, you were somewhere in Europe, for example,
где-то были в европе например
that is, you saw how people live there,
то есть вы видели как там люди живут
for example,
например
not me, just ask me to
не я просто просто спрашивать чтобы я
understand,
понял
I just wanted to understand, or did you see a
я просто хотел понять или вы видели
normal life once,
нормальную жизнь когда-то
I just see that you never  were not
я просто смотрю что вы никогда не были в
civilized in developed countries, so that
развитых странах цивилизованных так то
is, you and your UT-2 did not leave the city there by force of the city
есть вы и своего ут-2 силой там города
how many towers in your village how many towers in the village of the
поселке сколько башен в поселке
population
населения
in Turkey yes went there 4-star
в турции да поехали там 4-звездочный
hotel for a rest ok well here is your
отель по отдыхали окей хорошо вот вашем
village how many people  lives for
поселке сколько людей живёт
minutes, so that I understand how
минут да чтоб я понял в насколько
large a city you live in,
масштабном городе вы живете
how many people
то сколько населения
there are 6000, there is a small town, it is
6000 есть маленький городок это
very small, that is, depressive,
очень до небольшой то есть депрессивные
most likely, that is, we now have other
скорее всего то есть мы теперь другие
reasons because look at
причины потому что смотрите
such small towns, they are even depressive in the
такие маленькие городки они даже в
suburbs because there is
подмосковье депрессивные потому что там
no one there  -something there is development right from there
нету какой-то там развитие прямо оттуда
people usually leave so not
люди уезжают обычно так не
not or just yes I just agree and
не или просто да я согласна просто и
between what are you besides this g
между что вы вот кроме вот этого городка
you didn’t see anything but the
вы не видели ничего кроме как
Turks,
турки
that is, in Europe, you are, well, Russia, this is a
то есть в европе вы ну так россия это
setup country,
подстава страна
calculation, why, but maybe you looked at
расчет а почему но может быть посмотрели
how people live,
как люди живут
what did you look at, for example, how people
что вы посмотрели например как люди
live, I’ll look at you were as bold
живут я просмотрю вы были такие дерзкие
as I started to ask where is  you
как я вот начал спрашивать а где же вы
were and you immediately shut up they we don’t
были и вы сразу по умолкнуть они нам не
need allegro
нужен аллегрова
[music]
[музыка]
in you look you
в вы смотрите вы
just I see that people from Russia they are
просто я я смотрю что люди из россии они
all of them always, as it were, sitting in
все они всегда вот как бы сидят в своих
their trees here so but the forest there
вот этих деревьях так но лесу там
saved Ukraine there in Ukraine whom
украину спаса там в украине кого-то
-so save from whom
спасать так от кого
look because wait because you
смотри потому что подожди потому что вы
support
поддерживаете
where I attacked you why do you need you
куда мне на вас напали зачем мы вам вы
we need what documents
нам нужны какие документы
and
а
where we where would we attack now tell me where
куда мы куда бы напали вот скажите куда
would they attack what city
бы напали на какой город
here you really do you really think that we
вот вы реально вы реально думаете что мы
would  the second army of the world would be attacked
бы на вторую армию мира напали бы а
and you and we were sitting with Putin and burning
а вы а мы сидели с путиным и горите
so that or yes but
чтобы или да а
wait but
ну подождите а об биолаборатории слух
you heard about the biolaboratory
слышали про биолаборатории
you
вы
heard about the biolaboratories you heard about the biolaboratories in ukraine
слышали про биолаборатории в украине
there is a
есть
god in ukraine, then I wanted this
бог то я вот это хотел
[music]
[музыка]
then where was the
то где к вид изобрели
tap virus invented where I made
кран вирус где я сделали
[music]
[музыка]
I wanted to clarify about the laboratories how many
я про лаборатории хотел уточнить сколько
biological laboratories there were in Ukraine
было лабораторий в украине биологических
, it turns out
получается
that the coronavirus was invented in Ukrainian
то коронавирус изобрели в украинских
laboratories
лабораториях
on Russian soldiers
на русских солдатах
on whose soldiers they tested  but
на чьих солдатах испытывали а
how is it that the coronavirus seems to have
как же как же коронавирус у вроде же
started from China, not a tooth, not from Ukraine,
начался он с китая не зуб не с украины
that is, it turns out that the West
то есть получается запад
Biden forced Putin to attack
байден заставил путина напасть на
Ukraine, so
украину так
it’s bad that we have weapons,
что плохо что у нас есть оружие хорошо
we defend ourselves well and
мы защищаемся и
what
что
they say
говорят
no, we just help, yes, they help
нет просто помогаем ну да помогают
well,
хорошо
no  yes, let's say, let's say in the
нет да пусть допустим допустим в
Ukrainian army, if you
украинской армии если
look at what your
вот смотрите чем чем вам вот вашим
downtrodden village will be the best from an
забитом поселке будет лучший от
attack in Ukraine, the
нападения в украине
border
граница
[music],
[музыка]
not that is, to protect you here in your
не то есть по защите вам вот вашим
downtrodden village, so it will be better
забитом поселке так что будет лучше
that
что